Behind every little fish is a great white lie.
Shark Tale is a animation, action, comedy film directed by Vicky Jenson.
Oscar is a small fish whose big aspirations often get him into trouble.
Meanwhile, Lenny is a great white shark with a surprising secret
that no sea creature would guess: He's a vegetarian.
When a lie turns Oscar into an improbable hero and Lenny becomes
an outcast, the two form an unlikely friendship.
Oscar (voice), played by Will Smith.
Don Lino (voice), played by Robert De Niro.
Angie (voice), played by Renée Zellweger.
Lenny (voice), played by Jack Black.
Lola (voice), played by Angelina Jolie.
Ernie (voice), played by Ziggy Marley.
Shark Tale is a 2004 American animated adventure film directed by Vicky Jenson, Bibo Bergeron, and Rob
Letterman (in his feature length directorial debut), and written by Letterman and Michael J.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, the film features the voices of Will Smith, Robert De
Niro, Renée Zellweger, Angelina Jolie, Jack Black, and Martin Scorsese.
It follows an underachieving fish named Oscar (Smith) who falsely claims to have killed the son of a
shark mob boss Don Lino (De Niro) in an attempt to advance his community standing.
Oscar teams up with the mobster's younger son
Lenny (Black) to keep up the facade.
Shark Tale premiered at the Venice Film Festival on September 10, 2004, and
was theatrically released in the United States on October 1.
It made $374.6 million worldwide against its $75 million budget, finishing
its theatrical run as the ninth-highest-grossing film of 2004.
The film received mixed reviews from critics; advocacy groups criticized
the film for its use of Italian-American stereotypes.
It was nominated for Best Animated Feature at the 77th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of fish, secret love,
hero, mission of murder, vegetarian.
The tone is lighthearted.